DORJEY SHERPA

Elmhurst, NY, 11373 | 646-703-3586 | dorjeys3@gmail.com | GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn

DATA SCIENCE

Experience in data acquisition and data cleaning, statistical analysis, machine learning, and NLP. With a background in sales and research, I bring strong skills in data cleaning, critical thinking and communication to help innovative companies achieve their best products, projects, and end results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, SQL, Scikit-learn, Selenium, BeautifulSoup, NumPy, Pandas, NLTK, Gensim, MatplotLib, Seaborn, Plotly, HTML/CSS, Git, Github

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Walmart Product Review using Natural Language Processing - Github

- Used NLP and ML models to study Walmart's product reviews to predict whether an item will be recommended or not by the customers. Finally, based on the findings, recommended 2 major changes that could improve Walmart's online marketing tactics
- Scraped data from Walmart website using Selenium and BeautifulSoup
- Performed data cleaning, preprocessing and feature engineering using Pandas, Numpy, NLTK, Gensim
- Improved F1 score from a 0.68 to 0.88 after iterating over multiple models using Scikit-learn library

Predicting Cancellations on Hotel Reservations - Github

- Created a ML model that will predict what causes hotel cancelations and how to resolve that
- Studied and analyzed the data to find major differences between City Hotel and Resort Hotel
- Created a series of data visualizations using Matplotlib and Seaborn to compare the two hotels
- Using scikit-learn, we were able to generate 2 recommended models depending on the hotel's choice of action.

Apple Product Launch Analysis - Github

- Conducted a twitter Sentiment Analysis on Apple products for late 2020 Tech launches.
- Data was retrieved from Twint by searching 8 specific keywords new apple products and technologies
- Used NLTK and Gensim to study the tweets and conducted topic modeling

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Wholesale Representative, Shindo USA Inc, NY, NY

08/2019 - 09/2020

- Demonstrated and articulated new product releases to Fashion Brands (small and large/fast and luxury fashion)
- Gained understanding of customers' corporate strategies and operational functions to deliver the best products for their needs
- Reestablished connections with non-active clients and grew sales from \$0 to \$50K from non-active clients.

Shift Manager, Starbucks Coffee Company, NY, NY

02/2018 - 07/2019

- Communicated with facilities team to ensure store is in top shape to function and provide high quality products
- Listened and engaged with customers, while managing the floor, deploying people to their stations to ensure timely customer service

Research Assistant, Middlebury College, Middlebury, VT

09/2015-12/2017

- Designed and conducted research to contribute to Million Mutation Project
- Managerial duties such as budgeting, calling companies to gather more information on products, creating purchase orders and prepared the necessary solutions and materials to facilitate research in the lab

Teachers Assistant, Middlebury College, Middlebury, VT

09/2015-12/2017

- Organized, prepared and ordered the necessary materials and solutions to conduct experiments for students
- Facilitated tutoring sessions (6-10 hrs/wk) to assist students and guided students through laboratory techniques and skills

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY

09/2020 - 01/2021

Immersive Data Science Bootcamp Program

Middlebury College, Middlebury, VT

05/2017

Major: Neuroscience

Languages: English, Hindi, Nepali, Tibetan